Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

Summary

Software engineer with 8+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications.

Skills: agile, amazon web services (aws), api, azure, ci/cd pipelines, C#, css, databases, docker, express, git, grafana, html, java, javascript, jira, kafka, kotlin, kubernetes, linux, macOS, .NET, nodejs, project management, python, reactjs, scrum, seo, sql, typescript, version control, Windows

Experience

Senior Software Engineer GEICO Tech · Full-Time

Apr 2024 - Present · Remote

- Design, develop, & maintain GEICO's Sales API (SAPI), a high-traffic backend service that powers insurance quotes for customers and strategic partners (e.g. Credit Karma, Experian).
- Lead backend engineering initiatives, delivering new features and optimizations that enhance performance, scalability, and reliability.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration with GEICO's next-generation Sales Platform, supporting both legacy and modern architectures.
- Tech Stack: .NET, C#, Microsoft Azure, Domain-Driven Design, CosmosDB, SQL

Software Engineer

Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$

- Became a key contributor within the first month, joining on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and shipping production code, ensuring the MAX app launched on schedule in May.
- Led the design and implementation of novel integration tests using Jest, improving test coverage and system reliability.
- Developed Grafana dashboards and Terraform-based monitoring/alerting for MAX services, enhancing observability and incident response.
- Spearheaded the onboarding of a Golang service inherited through a reorganization, collaborating with three cross-functional teams to successfully integrate and operationalize the service before contract completion.
- Tech Stack: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker

Software Engineer

Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 – Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- Designed and built a high-traffic system using Kotlin and AWS, serving 100,000+ Alexa customer requests daily across multiple global regions.
- Developed an internal React.js web application to create and manage Alexa's content, integrating Puppeteer and Jest for testing and configuring DNS, routing, load balancing, and OAuth2 authentication.
- Implemented dynamic filtering logic to deliver personalized Alexa responses, leveraging GraphQL for seamless integration with multiple team APIs.
- Led a major content migration from a legacy CMS to ACMS/ARMS, successfully completing a three-month migration by developing bulk migration scripts and collaborating with engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales.
- Drove hiring efforts, conducting 50+ technical interviews in Q1 2022, directly contributing to team growth and earning a
 quarterly leadership award.
- Tech Stack: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git

Software Engineer

Cockroach Labs · Full-Time

May 2019 − Sep 2019 · New York, NY

- Contributed to the Bulk I/O team, enhancing bulk database operations such as backup, restore, and schema migrations.
- Resolved a critical issue in the dump operation, preventing interleaved table statements from causing dependency failures during restoration.
- Designed and implemented improvements to the backup & restore process, incorporating additional cluster metadata and streamlining the workflow to reduce manual intervention by the customer.
- Tech Stack: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

Software Engineer

Dataminr · Full-Time

Sep $2018 - \text{Feb } 2019 \cdot \text{New York, NY}$

- Developed tools for real-time search and filtering of high-volume data streams from Twitter and other media sources.
- Contributed to a large-scale JVM-based system (Scala/Java) running on AWS, leveraging Kinesis for streaming and S3 for data storage.
- Led the migration of the Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka, coordinating with multiple teams to ensure a smooth transition and maintain data integrity.
- Tech Stack: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, MacOS.

Software Engineer

IBM Corporation · Full-Time

Jul 2017 - Aug 2018 · Yorktown Heights, NY

- Developed a Python-based data migration application, collaborating with cross-functional teams to transition locally stored user data and accounts to IBM Bluemix (now IBM Cloud), improving scalability and accessibility.
- Designed and built a full-stack web application from the ground up using Angular, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap, implementing an MVC design pattern for efficient navigation & maintainability.
- Containerized and optimized deployment workflows using Docker, ensuring smooth and repeatable deployments across multiple environments.
- Tech Stack: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, MacOS.

Freelance Web Development

Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon · Freelance

Feb
 2023 — Jan2024 · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- Designed and developed a full-featured website from scratch using React.js, AWS, and JavaScript, ensuring a successful launch for the salon's grand opening.
- Implemented SEO best practices, boosting the website to top search rankings for hair extensions in the local area, achieving 300+ organic clicks per month.
- Built a custom content management solution, allowing salon owners to edit employee information in real-time with a fully responsive UI.
- Managed the entire development lifecycle, collaborating with the salon owners and a junior UX designer to define requirements, project timelines, and feature demos.
- Tech Stack: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI, SEO

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017